Class Photograph Collection BCMS.0029
Brooklyn Collection
Class Photograph Collection
1904-2002
Brooklyn Collection
BCMS.0029
0.72 Cubic feet in 1 flat box
The Class Photograph Collection consists of group photographs from Brooklyn schools, spanning the years 1904-2002.
Accruals
Accruals are expected; the finding aid will be updated as more class photographs are acquired.
Provenance
This is a synthetic collection that has had and will continue to have accruals. The original group was purchased from Brian Merlis in April of 2013.
Related Materials
Also at the Brooklyn Collection:
Clippings files arranged by school name
Ephemera files arranged by school name
Yearbook Collection
High School Newspaper Collection
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by school name.
Access
Collection is located in the Brooklyn Collection at the Central Branch at Grand Army Plaza. The collection may only be used in the library and is not available through interlibrary loan. Requests to view the collection must be made at least 48 hours in advance of visit.
Scope and Contents
This small collection documents graduating classes at various public and private schools in Brooklyn. Additionally, there are two photographs of the staff of Boys High School's student publication, the Recorder. Some photographs list student names on the verso, but most do not.
Boys' High School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Private schools -- New York (State) -- New York.; Public schools -- New York (State) -- New York.
- Alexander Hamilton Vocational High School, June 1947 (Box 1)
- Arthur S. Somers JHS, 1941-1952 (Box 1)
  General
  Class 9BR, June 1941.
  Class 9-SP1, June 1949.
  Class 9-SP1, June 1952.
- Boys High School, 1904-1919 (Box 1)
  1906; June 1919.
  Staff of the Boys High School Recorder, c. 1904 and 1906.
- Boody Junior High School, 1939 (Box 1)
  Class 9B5, June 1939.
- Brooklyn College of Pharmacy, undated (Box 1)
- Dewey Junior High School, 1945 (Box 1)
  Class 9B1, 1945.
- Intermediate School 227 (E.B. Shallow), January 1934 (Box 1)
- Intermediate School 252K, 2002 (Box 1)
- Junior High School 84, 1930 (Box 1)
  Class RD1, 1930.
- Our Lady of Guadalupe School, 1935 (Box 1)
- Public School 26, January 1936 (Box 1)
  Class 8B1, January 1936.
- Public School 44, 1916 (Box 1)
- Public School 50, January 1921, January 1923 (Box 1)
- Public School 64, 1923 (Box 1)
  Class 8B graduation photo and class play photo, both 1923.
  Note: These items are stored with the Bella Gordon P.S. 64 Collection.
- Public School 76, April 1951 (Box 1)
- Public School 84 (Glenmore Junior High School), January 1924 (Box 1)
- Public School 89, June 1924 (Box 1)
  Note: This photo is rolled up.
- Public School 104, June 1917 and February 1918 (Box 1)
- Public School 114, February 1918 (Box 1)
- Public School 130, January 1944 (Box 1)
- Public School 145, June 1922 (Box 1)
- Public School 167, June 1930 (Box 1)
- Public School 175, 1955-1962 (Box 1)
  One folder containing 15 8x10 class photographs and candid classroom photographs, 1955-1962.
- Public School 193, June 1950 (Box 1)
- Public School 201, June 1937 (Box 1)
- Public School 238, June 1942 (Box 1)
- Unknown Catholic school, undated (Box 1)